A Guide to the Harry Harris Collection of Confederate Reports and Vouchers, 1862-1865
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Harry Harris Collection of Confederate Reports and Vouchers, 1862-1865
The Library of Virginia
19970
1 leaf and 24 pages.
Harry Harris
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchased 2 December 1927, from Harry Harris, 2614 Semmes Avenue, Richmond, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Collection of Confederate reports and vouchers, 1862-1865, gathered by Harry Harris of Richmond, Virginia, consists mainly of quartermaster records, unit strength reports, and individual soldiers' pay vouchers for the 31st Virginia Infantry Regiment, the 2nd Virginia Artillery Battalion, and the 22nd Virginia Infantry Battalion. The 2nd and 22nd Battalions were actually the same unit, which was organized in May 1862 from six companies in the 2nd Virginia Artillery Regiment. Also included is a unit strength report (morning report) dated 11 [or 18] April 1865 for a Georgia brigade commanded by Colonel Robert J. Henderson (1822-1891) in Major General Carter Littlepage Stevenson's (1817-1888) Division of the Army of Tennessee. This brigade officially was known as Cummings' Brigade.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Return, 1 March 1862, of Company C, 31st Virginia Infantry Regiment, noting numerical strength and providing namees of commissioned officers and of enlisted men who are absent or on extra or daily duty.
- Voucher No. 10, 4 August 1862, Captain Thomas E. Burfoot, Company A, 2nd Battalion, Virginia Artillery, for pay covering 31 May to 30 June 1862.
- Voucher No. 13, 9 September 1862, Captain John G. Turpin, A.C.S., 2nd Battalion, Virginia Artillery, for pay covering 31 May to 30 June 1862.
- Voucher No. 21, 25 October 1862, Lieutenant Thomas Smith, adjutant, 2nd Battalion, Virginia Artillery, for pay covering 30 June to 30 September 1862.
- Voucher No. 25, 27 October 1862, Captain William G. Jackson, Company D, 2nd Battalion, Virginia Artillery, for pay covering 23 May to 1 October 1862.
- Abstract of expenditures, [January 1863?], by Captain Jacob J. Hill assistant quartermaster for the 31st Virginia Infantry Regiment, listing nine individuals to whom vouchers were issued for supplies or non-military services furnished during the quarter ending December 1862.
- Return, [January 1863?], of Company C, 31st Virginia Infantry Regiment, noting numerical strength and providing namees of commissioned officers and of enlisted men who are absent or on extra or daily duty.
- Voucher No. 6, 28 February 1863, certain subscribers to Captain Jacob J. Hill, assistant quartermaster for the 31st Virginia Infantry Regiment acknowledging payment for non-military services.
- Voucher No. 22, 27 March 1863, Thomas S. Scott, ordnance sergeant, 22nd Battalion Virginia Infantry, for pay covering 31 December 1862 to 28 February 1863.
- Voucher No. 23, 28 March 1863, Lieutenant B. H. McGuire, Company D, 22nd Battalion Virginia Infantry, for pay covering 31 December 1862 to 31 January 1863.
- Abstract, [April 1863?], of forage issued at different camps by Captain Jacaob J. Hill, assistant quartermaster, 31st Virginia Infantry Regiment, listing twenty-two individuals to whom Hill issued foraged during the quarter ending 31 March 1863.
- Voucher No. 25, 9 May 1863, Lieutenant B. H. McGuire, Company D, 22nd Battalion Virginia Infantry, for pay covering 31 March to 30 April 1863.
- Morning report, 11 or 18 April 1865, of Henderson's Brigade (also known as Cummings' Brigade) containing the numerical strenght of the four units in the Brigade: 1st (Georgia) Confederate Regiment, 39th Georgia Regiment, 40th Georgia Battalion, and the 42nd Georgia Regiment. Brigade was commanded by Colonel Robert J. Henderson and was part of General Carter L. Stevenson's Division.